（オオノキ）岩のゴーレム！
Stone Golem!
叩き潰してくれるわ！
It will pulverize him!
（マダラ）木遁…。
Wood Style...
花樹界降臨！
Deep Forest Bloom!
おのれ…。
Damn you!
（エー）ぐぬっ…。
《やはり…》
As expected...
（メイ）近づいてくる…
どうします！？
It's coming closer...
What should we do?!
（綱手）あれは…　おじい様の！
That's... Grandfather's...!
風影！
（我愛羅）わかっている！
Kazekage!
I know!
なんだ？
なんて規模なの…。
What is it?
Look at the scale of that!
一瞬で　森をつくるなんて！
To create a forest in an instant!
みんな　花粉に気をつけろ！
吸い込むな！
Everyone, beware of the pollen!
Do not inhale it!
《樹界降誕ではなく
花樹界まで…。
Not just Deep Forest Emergence...
but Deep Forest Bloom as well?
カブトめ…！》
How dare that Kabuto!
《カブト：初代火影
千手柱間ほどの忍は→
There is no shinobi alive today
who is as powerful as the First Hokage,
Hashirama Senju.
もう　いない。
人は皆　そう言う。
Everyone says that.
その強さを聞いた者は
六道仙人と同じく→
Just as they think that
the Sage of the Six Paths' power
was also a fairytale.
おとぎ話だとね…。
今こそ
そのおとぎ話を現実に…》
It's time to show them that
all the fairy tales were real!
（ゲンマ）待て　この野郎！
Wait, you bastard!
花に　気をとられすぎだ…。
You were too distracted by the flowers...
い　いかん…　雷影！
N-No! Raikage!
フッ…　火種も大きくいくとするか。
Humph... Time to burn things up...
火遁…　豪火滅失！
Fire Style... Majestic Demolisher!
ぐっ…。
ゲホッ…。
水影…。
Mizukage!
softness can overcome hardness, but hardness can overcome softness
juuyokugou wo seishimashite gouyokujuu motatsu
if you're too focused on showing off, my alarm will go off
muchuu de kakkou tsukete mo hijou beru ga naru
walk fifty steps forward in a reckless style
gojuuppo ijou mo saki aruite chottotsumoushinna sutairu
you're moody and do as you please; no matter what I do, you ignore me
jiyuu de kibunya no kimi wa douyattatte mushi
there's a mystery that no one can solve, I shiver when the wind blows
darenimo tokenai nazo ga aru fukidashita kaze ni furueteru
I'll unravel this maze
kono meiro wo hodoite yaru
you laughed, will it rain tomorrow?
kimi ga waratta ashita wa ame kai
the wise light flickers
soumeina hikari ga chikachika hikaru
you've got to focus your eyes before the future changes
me wo korasanakucha mirai ga kawatte shimau mae ni
I'm sure, I'm sure this moment will be swept away
kitto kitto ima wo saratte iku
I have to be with you, otherwise the future might dry up
kimi to janakucha mirai wa kawaite shimau no kamo
hurry up, because I'm sure that we'll smile back on this moment
isoge kitto ima wo waratte iku
The Will of Stone
水遁…。
Water... Style...
くっ…。
《やはり　歳か…。
I guess I am too old...
to do anything!
わしには　もう…》
((ほら　左が汚れちょる！
Look, the left side is dirty!
貴重な　岩隠れの石だぞ！
That's a precious rock of the Hidden Stone!
もっと　几帳面に磨かんかい！
Buff it more steadily!
強いストロークを基調に。
You need to put more polish
into your polishing!
《このダジャレが　きつい…》
His puns kill me...
フン？
Hmm?
里の象徴だか
なんだか知んねえけど→
Symbol of our village or not,
it's just a plain old rock.
どう見ても　ただの石ころだろ
こんなもん…。
木ノ葉みてえに　顔岩でも造りゃあ
サマになんのに→
Why don't we have Mountainside Images
like the Hidden Leaf?
うちの土影様は　安上がりな…。
Lord Tsuchikage is such a cheapskate!
オオノキ…
わしはな　石を見れば→
Ohnoki... I can tell the value of
a stone just by looking at it.
その石に
どんな価値があるか　わかる。
この石はな→
This rock...
symbolizes our village's Will of Stone!
我ら忍里の
固い意志の象徴じゃ！
It's our bedrock!
象徴まで　ダジャレにして
こじつけて　ケチってんなよ！
Don't be such a miser with your words
and use our symbol in your puns!
が　確かに
こんなものは　ただの石じゃ。
Well...
You're right.
This is just an ordinary rock.
え～っ！
Whaaaaaat?!
な…　なんてことすんだ！
クソジジイ！
W-What's the big idea,
you stupid old man!
どれだか　わかんねえぞ！
I can't tell which one it is now!
ほれ　こんなものは→
See... if you put a new one
here like this, no one would know.
こうして新しいのを
乗っけてもわかりはせん。
え～！
What?!
肝心なのは　己の中の意志じゃ。
What's important is
the Will of Stone inside you...
わしはな　人の意志を見れば→
You see, I can also tell the worth
of someone's will just by looking at them.
その意志が
どんな価値があるかもわかる。
オオノキ　お前の意志は
世界を変えうる力を秘めておる。
Ohnoki...
Hidden within your will is
the power to change the world.
じゃが　気をつけなくては→
But if you're not careful,
せっかくの　その意志も
なくなることがある。
that precious will of yours
may disappear...
なくなる？
Disappear?
なぜ？
Why?!
話が違う！　柱間殿は…。
That's not the agreement!
Lord Hashirama said...
同盟などない。
木ノ葉の力の前に　ただ従え。
There is no alliance.
Just obey the Hidden Leaf!
それと　俺の前で
その忍の名を口にするな。
And...
Never mention that shinobi's name
before me again!
スサノオ！
Susano'o!
壁じゃ！　壁に当たるうち→
Barriers! As you keep
running into barriers,
己の中の意志を捨て　言い訳し→
you may abandon your will...
make excuses and even
replace it with hatred.
かわりに憎しみを
拾うことになりかねん。
いいか　お前の意志→
Listen closely, your will...
捨てずに　すてきに　ステップじゃ！
Never abandon it and
always stride with pride!
まだ　踊りたいようだが→
Seems you still want to keep dancing...
(お前のは　踏み込みがなってない))
But there's no strength left in your step!
言い訳して…。
I'm making excuses...
塵遁　原界剥離の術！
Particle Style:
Atomic Dismantling Jutsu!
何が　「やはり歳か…」じゃ！
Look at me being pitiful about my age...
言い訳して
いいわけあるか…　じゃぜ！
I should be excused...
for making an excuse!
これは！？
オオノキ！
What's this?
Ohnoki!
起きたか　よっしゃ！
これからは反撃じゃぜ！
You're all awake!
All right!
Let's get on with our counterattack!
あそこか！
There he is!
よく踊る。
You dance well.
だが　踏み込みがまだ浅い。
But your step is still too weak.
あれは…　初代火影の顔！
That... looks like
the First Hokage's face!
まさかとは思ったが…
だから　木遁まで！
I didn't want to believe it, but...
That's why he's able to
use the Wood Style!
《ククク…　大蛇丸様が作った
ダンゾウの試作とは　わけが違うよ。
And this is far different from
what Lord Orochimaru developed
with Danzo.
マダラより強かった初代火影。
The First Hokage was more
powerful than Madara.
そして　この２人を融合した
これは　僕の切り札！
This fusion of both will be
my ultimate weapon.
この穢土転生は
誰も止められない！》
No one can stop
this Reanimation!
（サスケ）待て！
Wait!
イタチなのか！？
Is that you, Itachi?!
待てって言ってんだろうが！
I said... wait!
《スサノオ！》
Susano'o!
このスサノオ
やはり　お前は　イタチ！
This Susano'o...
So you are Itachi!
（イタチ）まさか→
I'm surprised that you've been
able to master it too...
お前まで　これを
使えるようになっているとはな。
なぜ　あんたがここにいる！
死んだはずだ！
What are you doing here?!
You're supposed to be dead!
カブトの術…。
This is Kabuto's jutsu...
今の俺は　穢土転生だ。
I'm a Reanimation now.
今は　止まっていられない。
I can't stop now.
There's something I have to do.
やらなければならない
ことがある。
そんなの知るか！
I don't care!
あんたが　こうして
俺の目の前にいる。
You're here before me and
I have a lot of questions!
聞きたいことが
山のようにある！
あとにしろ。
Ask me later... But I guess
that's not going to happen.
と　言っても聞かないか。
あんたが言ったんだ！
You said so yourself!
俺と同じ眼を持って
俺の前に来いと！
To come find you once
I had the same eyes as you!
なら　なぜ逃げる！
So why are you running?
俺に　ウソをついた
後ろめたさか？
To avoid admitting
that you lied to me?!
それとも
真実を語る勇気がないからか？
Or don't you have
the courage to tell the truth?!
俺は　もう
あんたのすべてを知ってる！
I already know...
everything about you!
だから　俺は
木ノ葉を潰すと決めたんだ！
That's why I decided to destroy
the Hidden Leaf!
お前と戦ったとき　言ったはずだ。
I told you when we fought...
人は　思い込みのなかで
生きている。
That people live
under false assumptions...
そう考えられないかと。
I asked if you could think
about it that way.
その現実は　幻かもしれないと。
And how one's reality
might be an illusion.
俺の真実が本当に…。
Is my truth really—
俺はもう　幻の中にはいない！
I no longer live
inside an illusion!
あんたの幻術を見抜ける！
And I can see through
your genjutsu!
これは…　あんたの眼だ！
These are your eyes!
((ナルト：あんたの苦しみも覚悟も→
Sasuke understands
your suffering and your resolve!
サスケは理解しているはずだ。
でも　サスケは　あんたの意志を
受け継ぐどころか→
But instead of
carrying on your will,
木ノ葉を潰す気でいる。
he intends to destroy
the Hidden Leaf!
それは
大好きだった兄貴を苦しめた→
That's his way of getting back
at the village that caused
(里への
弔い合戦のつもりなんだろう))
his beloved older brother
so much suffering!
強気な物言いは変わってないが→
You're as confident as ever,
お前のその後は　人から聞いた。
but I've heard about you
from others.
ずいぶん変わったと。
That you've changed a lot...
違う！　あんたが　かつて
俺のすべてを変えたんだ！
No! You changed everything
about me!
俺は　死ぬはずだった。
I was supposed to die!
両親と一緒に
あんたに殺されるはずだった！
You were supposed to kill me
along with our parents.
なのに…。
But...
((そこで　イタチは　決めたのだ。
So Itachi made his decision.
己の手で　一族の歴史に
幕を下ろすことを。
That he would drop the curtain
himself on his own clan's history.
うちはを憎み
裏切ったのではない。
He did not betray out of hatred.
しかたなかったのだ。
It was unavoidable.
里の興りからの差別
そして　確執のツケ。
The discrimination by the village...
and the object of
their antagonism...
それを
たった一人で背負い込み→
He shouldered everything
all by himself.
己を犠牲にした
イタチの決断を責めることは→
No one can ever question
Itachi's decision
(誰にもできまい))
and the sacrifice he made.
((なんだよ　これ…。
What is this?!
兄さん！　父さんと母さんが…。
Brother! Mother and Father were...
なんで…　どうして！
いったい誰が　こんなことを！
Why?
Who could have done this?
愚かなる弟よ。
Foolish brother...
Mangekyo Sharingan!
(万華鏡写輪眼！))
なぜ　俺だったんだ！
Why me?!
なぜ　俺だけ残した！
Why did you spare me?!
((どうしても
お前を殺せなかった。
He just couldn't bring himself
to kill you.
(その意味がわかるか？))
Do you know what that means?
なぜ　俺が…
父や母と何が違う！？
Why me?!
How was I different from
mother and father?
なぜ　俺ばかりが…。
Why just me?
お前は　当時
何も知らなかった。
Because you didn't know anything.
うちは一族の愚考も何も…。
子供だった。
You had no part in
the Uchiha Clan's folly.
You were just a child.
そして　お前のためだけではない。
Also, do you think
I did it just for you?
俺は　うちはである　お前の手で
裁かれたかったのだと思う。
I wanted to be judged and
dealt with only by another Uchiha.
そのために
お前の中の憎しみを利用した。
So I took advantage of
the hatred inside you.
だから　失敗したんだ。
That's why I failed.
結局　俺は
お前に憎しみを与え→
Ultimately, I filled you with hatred
and made you go rogue.
里を抜けさせ
罪人にしてしまった…。
And turned you into a criminal!
((千鳥！
エルボー！))
Chidori!
お前が正しい道を
歩いていくことを→
All I wanted was for you
to walk the right path.
願っていたのに…。
俺は　死ぬ以前より
お前が違う道に行かぬよう→
Before I died, I tried to lead you
分かれ道のない
一本道に誘い込むようにした。
down that one path
without any forks or turns...
道案内の立て札を→
I changed the signposts
ウソと瞳力で書き換えてな。
on that path with lies
and my Visual Prowess.
何も知らず　俺だけ　のんきに→
I was supposed to happily walk
that one path,
その一本道を歩くだけか！？
ignorant of everything?!
俺は…　そんな道を
望んじゃいない！
I... don't care for such a path!
ああ　確かにそうだ。
Yeah...
You're absolutely right.
どう行くかは
自分で決めるものだ。
You must decide your own journey.
いくら立て札を
書き換えようとも→
No matter how much you try
to rewrite the signposts,
もう俺の眼は
その上塗りを見抜く！
my eyes can strip away
the top layer!
フッ。
何が　おかしい！
What's so funny?!
いや…　道案内は→
Nothing...
I'm just realizing that
何も立て札ばかりじゃ
なかったんだな。
the signposts were
not your only guides.
俺は　本来　死人だ。
I'm a dead man.
これ以上は　語るまい。
There's no point in
talking any further.
あんたは　生前
俺にかまってくれず→
When you were alive,
you never paid any attention to me.
いつも　「許せ」と額を小突き→
Always flicking my forehead,
saying "forgive me"
and running off.
逃げるだけだった。
死んだ今でも
まだ逃げるのか！？
Now you're dead, and
you're still running away from me?!
逃げているわけではない。
I'm not running away.
言ったはずだ。
I told you.
やらなければならないことが
あると。
There's something I must do.
《イタチ：穢土転生を止めなければ》
I must stop... the Reanimation.
（マダラ）そこの医療忍術の女。
You there... woman,
user of the Medical Ninjutsu...
お前　こいつの血を引いているな？
You have his blood running
through your veins, don't you?
だったら何だ！
And what of it?!
まずは　お前から叩く。
I'll bring you down first.
クッ。
小隊の医療忍者を
まず叩くのは定石。
Taking out a unit's Medic Ninja
first is an established tactic.
それをわかっている
こっちが→
Surely, you don't think we'd
let you do that so easily, do you?
簡単にやらせると
お思いで？
（マダラ）違う…。
You're wrong...
その女が
千手柱間の子孫だからだ。
It's because she's a descendant
of Hashirama Senju.
お前ごときの
医療忍術とやらは→
Your Medical Ninjutsu
is only strong enough
死をほんの少し
先のばしにしているにすぎん。
to defer death for
only a short while.
千手柱間と比べれば
取るに足らぬ術だ。
Compared to Hashirama Senju,
your jutsu is trivial.
（マダラ）やつは
印を結ぶことすらなく→
He was able to heal without
even weaving signs.
傷を治すことができた。
すべての術が　ケタ違い。
He was in another class
in every jutsu.
人は　やつを最強の忍と呼んだ。
Everyone called him
the most powerful shinobi.
やつとは
命懸けの戦いをしたものだ…。
I fought a real death match
against him...
こんな遊びではなくな。
This is child's play.
それに比べて…。
Compared to him, what do you,
his descendant, have to offer?
柱間の子孫でありながら
お前には　何がある？
木遁も使えず→
You can't even use the Wood Style...
柱間の足もとにも　およばない
医療忍術。
Your Medical Ninjutsu
doesn't even come close.
そして　何より…　か弱い女。
And most of all,
you're a weak woman!
弱い者は　醜い。
Weakness disgusts me.
弱い千手など　なおさらだ！
And a weak Senju disgusts me
even more!
グチャグチャと
偉そうに言わせておけば！
You've gone on long enough!
ん？
私は　初代柱間の子孫だが→
I am a descendant of
the first Hokage Hashirama...
確かに　木遁は使えない！
And true,
I don't use the Wood Style.
医療忍術も
印を使わぬ初代に比べれば→
My Medical Ninjutsu is pathetic
compared to the First's,
who didn't even
have to weave signs!
たいしたことはない。
それに　私は女だ。
And I am a woman...
と言っても
か弱い女ってのは違うが…。
A woman, yes...
But not a weak woman.
フッ。
単純な力などではない。
Simple strength isn't everything.
初代から引き継がれ
流れ続けるものが→
It's something passed on to me,
and continues to flow
from the First Hokage.
私の本当の力だ！
That is my true power!
火の意志をなめるなよ！
So don't you dare underestimate
the Will of Fire!
let's keep walking
itsuka kitto kitto tadori tsuku tame ni
so we'll be sure to get there someday
ima wa madamada arukou
when I was young, I had a guitar as a toy
osanai koro te ni shita omocha kawaridatta gitaa
we just made noises, but that was enough to keep me engrossed
tada otowodasu hontou soredakeni muchu ni natte ita
giving up seems simple, but it's incredibly difficult
akirameru no wa kantan na youde ichiban muzukashii
I'll start singing today too
sousa boku wa kyou mo utau yo
I believe that my dream will come true I want to believe
dakara sou yume wa kanau shinjitai shinjitai
if I reach even one person
tatta hitori demo todoite kuretara
until I lose my voice
kono koe kareru made
I believe that everyone's dream can come true, I want to believe
dare demo yume wa kanau shinjiteru shinjiteru
the future is sure to change to a color you like better
dakara motto motto mirai wa korekara sukinairo ni kawaru yo
let's hold on to our dreams
yume wo daite arukou
This Reanimation Jutsu will not
come undone even if you kill me.
But I am the only one
who can stop it.
＜昭和３０年代と４０年代の
思い出の名曲を大特集。
In other words, you can't kill me.
I'll make you stop the Reanimation.
当時　青春時代を送っていた
皆さんの…＞
This jutsu has neither risks
nor weaknesses.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Risks of the Reanimation Jutsu"
＜　それぞれの年のベスト３を発表＞
Every jutsu has a weakness.
＜２０年分の名曲を
たっぷりお届けします＞